Hey, Dad,
did you get
stuck in traffic?
How many times
have I told you?
No biking on Sunset.
You wanna be some movie
producer's roadkill?
I bought you
the Beemer
for a reason.
Okay, okay.
I'll drive it.
Up the 101 Freeway
to UC Santa Barbara.
Dana...
Have you even looked
at the catalog I gave you?
You're gonna study
fish and surf all day?
I can't even talk to you.
Hey, you've got
a free ride
to a top school.
You're going, case closed.
Why?
So I can score
some high-paying job
rotting behind
some desk all day
to pay for all this?
Okay, maybe "rotting"
was a poor choice.
I don't have time for this.
You never have time.
Dad, I appreciate
you work hard,
I really do.
But I would suffocate
in that world.
I'm like Mom,
I'm too much of
a free spirit.
Where did you get that,
"free spirit"?
It's from her journal, Dad.
You should never have
brought her to LA.
This is what
really killed her,
not the cancer.
Dana, give me a break.
You were five years old,
you barely knew her.
High five.
It's funny.
Get that camera
out of my face.
Look at that,
it's right over there.
Come on, guys.
Come on, lunch is ready.
Daddy,
can I try the camera?
Dana,
go get your bucket,
the waves are gonna get it.
Go get your bucket
out of the sea.
This is fun.
Look out,
that's a big wave.
Come, let's build
a sand castle.
I'm gonna get you.
Last night I had a dream
where I took my little Dana
back home to South Africa
with me
and showed her
the Bay of Plenty
and Cave Rock,
Vulamanzi Point
and Banana Reef.
All the way down
the Wild Coast to
Coffee Bay and Bruce's.
Finally we reached
Jeffrey's Bay,
the one place I've always
dreamed of surfing.
If only I could
take her there.
If only she could
see these places, maybe
she could see me, too.
But that can
never happen now.
I'm out of time.
And I'm afraid
I'll never get
back home.
Dad, by the time
you get back from
your business trip,
I'll be in South Africa.
I think you and I could
use some time apart.
And I think it's time
I learned more about Mom.
It's just something
I have to do.
Don't worry about me.
I'll be fine, as always.
Love, Dana.
First trip
to South Africa?
Yeah, it is.
Visiting family?
Um...
Kind of.
Well, enjoy.
Thank you.
Let me guess,
California girl going south
to find winter swell.
Is it that obvious?
Well, flight to Durban,
surf city.
Roxy sunglasses,
ocean hair.
How very CSI of you.
Well,
that and The Bomb.
Ah!
Well, every surfer gets it.
Yeah.
I'm Grant.
Dana.
Nice to meet you,
California girl.
Where you headed?
I don't have a plan.
Nice.
A real beach bum.
Yeah.
Well, if you make it
down south, look me up.
I'll buy you
a smoothie at my bar.
It's called
Sally Can't Surf.
Cool, thanks.
Pleasure.
Taxi? Taxi?
Miss, where
are you going?
Where can I catch
a bus to the beach?
There are no buses
today, miss.
Hey! What are
you doing?
Special holiday.
Have a good price.
No problem,
I'll give good price.
Attention, passengers.
This bus is leaving
for Durban City Beach
in two minutes.
Sorry.
Move the bag.
I'm sorry,
this seat's taken.
Yeah? Who takes it?
Her.
Hey, you're late.
I saved you a seat.
Pushy.
I'll say.
What a creep.
I mean,
my name is Pushy.
Oh.
That's unusual.
What does it mean
in your language?
Pushy.
Like "pushy"?
Actually, my Zulu
name is Nokuthula.
Which means...
"Be quiet."
What?
Never seen a white girl
riding the bus before.
Well, I've never seen
a black girl who surfs.
Well, if you're lucky,
maybe you'll get
a chance to observe it
for the first time.
Maybe you'll
learn something.
Well, if that
particular scenario
presents itself,
don't be surprised
if I'm not the one
who gets schooled.
That's New Pier.
She throws killer sets
almost every day.
Best spot in the city.
Let's do it.
You cool?
Yeah, I'll see you there.
Looks decent.
Decent?
Better than Malibu,
I bet.
My advice to you
is to sit wide,
smile, wait for
a wrap-around set
and maybe you'll catch
a little ride.
Shit.
What?
Don't tell me you're afraid
of 4-foot waves.
No, it's not the waves,
it's her. Tara.
Wow, Tara can surf.
So, what do we do,
just jump in?
Sometimes it's the only way.
It's mobbed enough out here,
go surf South Beach.
There's plenty ofwaves
out here, Tara.
Yeah, for me.
Not you,
or Barbie there.
Hey, you stay out of my way
and I'll stay out of yours.
Yeah? You better
explain the pecking order
to her, Push.
Hate to have
to educate her
the hard way.
Let's go. I hate
this aggro vibe.
Hell, no. I just flew
23 hours in coach.
I'm surfing.
Gidget alert.
Coming through.
You here for
your surf lesson?
Hey, Baywatch,
how you doing?
Did your daddy buy you
an antique surf board?
I got it.
No, you don't.
Wow.
Yeah, it was a nice wave.
No, I mean, whoa,
you stole one from
the queen bee.
Talk about getting schooled.
Yeah, Tara needs to
loosen her sphincter up.
Let's go.
Great. Now every knob
thinks they can surf.
Outside!
Out of the way, Barbie.
Move!
Hey, I said
I had it. Hey!
Shit!
What do you think
you were doing?
Shit!
You could have killed me!
Get out of the water,
you idiot!
You dropped in
on her, Tara!
Damn it!
Why do you have
to be such a...
Such a what?
God!
That's right. Run away.
And don't come back!
Is that how it is
in South Africa?
Screw her.
You snagged the barrel
of the day out there.
Right in their faces.
Yeah, but I busted
my board!
Better the board
than your head.
It was my mom's.
I can't replace it.
I can't believe it!
No. No, no.
This can't be happening.
Shit.
Your money?
I don't care about that.
My mother's carving's gone.
Yeah. These lockers
are pretty flimsy.
Really?
You know what?
I'm sorry.
Can you just
leave me alone?
Please?
Dana, give me a break.
You barely knew her.
Hi, I'd like
to make a collect call
to the United States.
Area code 310-467...
You must be hungry.
We're grilling
a fish tonight.
Hang up.
Come on, give it
one more chance.
What kind of fish?
My dad would freak
if he saw me doing this.
He would drag me
home for sure.
Well, if he knew
where I was.
Your dad doesn't know
you're in Africa?
Oh, man. You are
in trouble, girl.
No, I doubt that.
I'm actually not sure
he even knows I'm gone.
What?
Thanks, man.
Thank you.
Cheers.
This is where
you live?
Yes.
And these people
are my family.
Hey, guys.
Hi.
This might
be paradise.
Wait a minute.
What the hell is
she doing here?
Uh...
She lives here.
What?
She lives with you?
All right, strike
"paradise," insert "hell."
What is her deal anyway?
For starters, she's
a professional athlete.
She's the number one
on the Roxy team,
and she doesn't let
anyone forget it.
I thought I said something
about "don't come back."
Yet here you are again,
like a bad memory.
It's not just
your house, Tara.
No, but there's
a pecking order,
just like the line-up.
Yeah, well,
your pecking order
doesn't work for me.
Cops are back.
You know what to do.
Not again.
We'll take this up later.
Come on.
TARA: Let's go!
By order of the
eThekwini Metropolitan
Municipality,
this property is condemned
and must be
vacated immediately.
Care to fill me in?
They want us out of here.
We're a nuisance.
They really want to
tear the place down.
This is your final warning.
This structure
will be demolished
in one week.
By order of the court,
this is your final warning.
Piss balloons.
Oh!
Disgusting!
This is your last warning.
You have one week to get out.
Come on,
I'll introduce you
to the family.
We laid claim to
this beach years ago.
At first it was
just a couple of tents
and some surf boards.
Now it's
a self-sustaining
community.
Really, it's just a bunch of
friends who are serious about
goofing off and riding waves.
Welcome.
I like your family.
Best people in the world.
I met them all through Tim.
Hey!
Whoa!
Speak of the devil.
Timothy, say hi to Dana.
Hey.
Hi.
You from LA?
Yeah. I got in today.
You staying?
I don't know.
That means you're staying.
Okay, Pushy,
let's show her
the best part.
You all right?
My humble abode.
Cool. Does it run?
If I have my way,
it will. Someday.
That's lots of elephants.
Yeah, I volunteer at
the nature reserve.
In between being one of
the best board shapers around.
And our go-to fix-it man.
Hence the mess.
But I can move some
of this stuff if you
need a place to stay.
Nice try!
She's staying with me.
Come on.
Careful, Dana,
you've seen how we deal
with blow-ins around here.
She's staying
with me, Tara.
Just stay out of my way.
My pleasure.
So, it's not the Hilton,
but it's not so bad.
Yeah, I could hang
with this for a while.
Ha!
I see Laura and Sally,
all the top Roxy riders,
but I don't see Tara.
I must have
missed her somehow.
Uh-huh.
Girl has it made, hey?
Travel the world,
surf killer waves all day,
pose for the cameras
and get paid for it.
Why don't you try
out for the team?
I did.
Didn't make the cut.
Why? You can rip,
I saw you.
Or...
Or?
Or Tara screwed me over.
Wow. Well, I wouldn't
put it past her.
Yeah, one big,
happy family.
That's what we are.
You jet-lagged?
Maybe a little.
Dana?
Dana!
Hey, sister!
Okay, be cool.
I am cool.
No, be cool.
Okay.
Look, it's a zombie.
Night of the living Dana.
Food. Give me food.
Voila.
Whoo!
Oh, my God. That's, like,
the best fish I've ever had.
Well, that's good,
'cause it's the
main course tomorrow.
And the next night.
And breakfast.
Nice.
Hey. Grant.
Hey.
Hey, Sugaree.
I don't believe it.
You know Grant?
I met him
on the plane,
briefly.
Fifty bucks says
he was flying first class.
How do you know?
Grant's the only one
that can afford
a truck like that.
I wish I had one.
TlM: Trust me,
you don't want to
get mixed up in that.
Come on, I'll show you
the giant sea turtles.
They lay their eggs
just up the beach.
California girl!
I had a feeling you'd
show up before long.
Small world, huh?
Yeah.
Pushy brought me here.
Oh, Pushy.
Bro.
I owe you one.
I do, I do.
So, California girl,
are you gonna show us
what you got?
I don't know.
Come on.
You feel the groove.
Come on. Come on.
Can you hold this?
"Let me show you
the giant sea turtles"?
Seriously?
Shut up.
California girl can dance.
Pushy?
See ya.
Morning, California girl!
Hey.
Jet-lagged?
I'm here, aren't l?
Can't believe
those two are friends.
They seem so different.
The love of the ocean
brings different
spirits together.
I think they might
both love something
else, too.
I'm not going there.
Oh, yeah?
Think I might have
seen your lips
go there last night.
Maybe a little
tongue, too.
Right.
Go ahead, girl.
You got this.
Show 'em what you got.
I'm all over it.
Go for it,
California girl!
Whoo!
Go, girl!
Keep up, old man.
I'm trying!
Go get 'em, Tim.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Yeah!
Whoo!
You don't
remember her at all?
Just a few blurry images.
You know, like in a dream.
Her name was Catherine.
I was five years old.
TlM: Those are all
you have left?
And there was another
keepsake of hers, but
it got stolen with my stuff.
She always wanted
to show me her homeland.
Your mom was a hottie!
Well, like mother
like daughter.
Oh!
Yes. Check it, bro.
Classic Supertubes.
And not a soul out.
When was the last time
you saw J-bay like that?
Never.
She wrote
about Jeffrey's Bay
a lot in her journal.
Like it was
someplace sacred.
Sacred's the word.
Finest point break
in the world.
My old stomping grounds.
Oh! When J-bay fires
on all cylinders...
And the tubes are grinding
from the Boneyards,
through lmpossibles
right down to The Point...
The holy grail
of right-handers.
The holy grail.
She said it was
the one place that she had
to surf before she died.
But she never did.
No.
Probably couldn't.
But I will.
I'm gonna surf it for her.
You know what else?
I'm going to go to
every one of those
places in those photos.
Do you know what, Dana?
You're on Uhambo.
That's what we call it
in South Africa.
It's like when
someone's looking for...
What?
I don't know.
My mom, I guess.
Or maybe yourself.
In Australia
they call it
a walkabout.
In the Holy Land,
a pilgrimage.
What do you call it
in America?
Um...
A journey?
Boring.
Don't like it.
An odyssey?
Yes.
I like that.
An odyssey.
I call it a pipe dream.
You think it's still
Endless Summer out there?
It's a long, hard trip
down the Wild Coast
before you get to J-bay.
Not to mention
winter's coming. Do you
even have a wetsuit?
Then it's sharks
in the ocean,
Iocals who demand
total respect, and
a heavy, heavy wave.
Beverly Hills girl here
wouldn't last a day
on her own.
Who says she's on
her own, Tara?
Dana, you and l
are going on this
odyssey together.
That's good,
the blind leading the blind.
I say they pull it off.
Hundred bucks says
they don't.
And I want evidence.
Pictures ofyou
at all those places.
And surfing them.
Of course.
You're on.
She'll never
surf J-bay.
I could
lend you my truck.
Really?
At a price.
You ever waited tables?
One of my waiters just quit.
Maybe Pushy can show you
the ropes here.
Sound good?
Sounds good.
All right.
Spare set.
Always be prepared.
It's a Land Rover.
You drive it hard,
you put it away wet.
We can do that.
Thanks, Grant.
You sure you don't
want to come with us?
Nah.
We can go for a spin later,
perhaps, when you get back.
Midnight, maybe.
Just you and me.
You're not that lucky.
Here you go.
Document your
odyssey properly.
Tim, where did you find
a Polaroid camera?
Junk shop in Durban.
Dug up some film as well.
That is so sweet of you.
I got one more thing.
Tim, this is amazing.
Do you know how few people
can fix a board like this?
Aw!
You fixed her board, dude,
and you just got cheek.
Be careful.
Tara may be half-joking,
but there's
a lot of bad things that
can happen out there.
You have a long highway
ahead of you.
Life is a highway
Thank you.
I wanna ride it
All night long
Life is a highway
I wanna ride it all night long
Yeah!
If you're goin' my way
I wanna drive it
all night long
"And I reached it
just as dawn broke,
my favorite time of the day.
"Difficult to find,
almost impossible
to leave."
That is some poetic shit.
I mean, that's deep.
Think so?
Sounds like she was
a first-rate mom.
She was.
At least I think she was.
I mean, I know
she was a free spirit.
Shit, all I know is
what's in that book.
In the memorable words
of my dad,
"l barely even knew her."
You know, I bet
you are a lot like her.
I hope so.
I live every day
with the fear that
I'll never know.
Yes. I can see it.
See what?
There it is!
It's a Land Rover.
Like Grant said,
you drive it hard
and put it away wet.
Whoo!
Yeah!
Hello.
Well, that was rude.
Looks pretty
free-spirited to me.
Yeah.
Dana and Pushy's odyssey,
step one, complete.
Put it away wet.
Hey, man,
put it away wet.
Hole in the Wall.
Done.
Cha-ching, baby.
Don't count
your pennies
just yet.
The rule around here
is the new girl
cleans the toilet.
Oh, come on.
Relax, it's not so bad.
Except when some oke
barks the dog after too
many klippies and coke.
A what?
You know,
parks a tiger.
Blows chunks.
Oh! Gross.
And by the way,
just in case you were
wondering what's in
this odyssey for me...
I was waiting for this.
In exchange for being
your trusty guide,
you will teach me
how to pull off
your 360 floater.
You're gonna try out
for the Roxy team again?
You are not the only
girl on a mission.
Hell, yeah.
Here.
This is Spike
from Wakescape
with your swell update.
That frothy low
that's been spinning
off Antarctica
has intensified over
the last 24 hours.
If it keeps
spinning like that,
we're due for
a macking southerly
groundswell
to hit the East Coast,
so you guys in J-bay
better start waxing up.
And now back to music...
You hear that, Flash?
J-bay is gonna be
all time, bro.
Screwdriver.
Thank you.
Fix the radio, man?
Walk this way.
Straight. On foot only.
Thank you.
Long way in, hey?
Uh... Pushy?
I guess we should
step aside.
Yeah, seems wise.
Your mom went to
some pretty far-out places.
Yeah, like Beverly Hills.
You know,
maybe that old guy
was yanking our chain.
Or maybe he wasn't.
This is why surfers
invent words.
Invent words?
You know, like
"gnarly" or "stoked."
Huh!
So, what do we do,
just jump in?
Sure, you go first.
Okay, the aerial 360.
Watch and learn.
Go for it, Push!
Come on!
You're good. Try again!
Look, because
you ride goofy you have to
nail this on your backhand.
It's a lot harder, Push.
No kidding.
You're gonna go down,
round and up.
From the flight deck
this is Captain Glen Ross.
We're beginning our final
descent into Durban.
Please fasten
your seat belts,
we'll be landing
in 10 minutes.
Mango smoothie,
easy on the ice, Push.
Look. Dana,
I think we just got off
on the wrong foot.
Mmm-hmm.
'Cause believe it or not,
I'm kind of rooting for you.
What, like you were
rooting for Pushy to
join the Roxy team?
She told you
I sabotaged her?
Yeah, that's bullshit.
The truth is,
she surfed like crap.
I was there.
She was out of shape
and unprepared.
Come on, you know it
takes hard work and
commitment to be on a team.
Some people have it,
some people don't.
I think you might
have it, Dana. Might.
There's an open tryout
in Jeffrey's Bay
next Saturday.
And since you're headed
that way anyway...
Yeah, it's not
my scene, Tara.
But Pushy will be there.
Sweet. So will l.
Good.
That's for you, Push.
Don't work too hard.
Even if I do
make it to J-bay,
she'll never let me
make the team.
Well, maybe that decision's
up to you and not her.
What?
Hey.
Who was that?
Who?
The guy in the truck.
Just some oke asking about
the surf here.
He didn't even have a stick.
So, you don't know him?
Nah. Never seen
him before.
Mmm.
Pushy,
I think I just saw
the guy who stole my stuff.
What? You sure?
You only saw him once.
Pushy, I need to get
my mom's stuff back.
What's so important
about this stuff anyway?
I mean, I know it was
your mom's, but...
It just... It just is.
Tell you what.
Shift's almost over.
Go home.
I'll cover for you.
Thanks, Push.
Tim.
Hey.
How's the odyssey coming?
It's coming.
Yeah?
Yeah. I'm just waiting
on the water now.
Yeah, I'm tracking
that for you.
You still got a couple of days
before the big swell comes.
Thanks.
No problem.
What?
Is it me, or do you
smell like an elephant?
Hey! Elephants don't smell.
That's pure man-sweat
you're taking in.
So, you had a long day
at the reserve, I smell.
Long but good.
You wanna see some pictures
while I get cleaned up?
Sure.
Yeah?
See the way they
take care of one another?
Looking after the old ones,
sick ones, young ones.
I heard they even mourn
when one of them dies.
Yeah, yeah,
I've seen that.
Unfortunately.
You lost one?
Rare, but we do have
some poachers around here.
Shit.
Gotta hand it
to 'em, though.
After they mourn
they just close ranks,
the family reorders itself
and they just move on.
Is that why
you're drawn to them?
What do you mean?
You know, the family thing.
Kind of like what
you've created here.
Huh.
Well, aren't you
a smart girl.
Mmm.
Not so smart.
I'm probably the last person
you should be listening to.
Hey, where
are you going?
You're not the only one
that has to shower.
Got a hot date tonight.
I'm going dancing
with Pushy.
Hey, let me know
about that swell.
First time in Durban, sir?
Well, first time
in about 20 years.
Hey, sister.
Hi.
This is it.
This is where I grew up.
And it's the best spot for
kwaito music and dancing.
Careful, sister.
Come on. You never seen
a white girl dance before?
I'm teaching you my moves,
show me some of yours.
Okay, then.
Watch how it's done.
Go, sister!
Hello, everyone. Let's
kick it in here all night.
You're ready?
Why are you here?
What the hell do you
want in my business?
Huh?
You keep looking for trouble,
I will show it to you.
Do you hear me?
Dana! Shit,
that was him!
We have to
call the cops.
Cops don't come to
the kasie! Dana. Dana!
This is insane.
Dana.
This is not worth it,
whatever it is.
I just wanna see
where he goes,
and we can come
back later for help.
Come on.
Dana.
What?
You don't know
what you're dealing with.
We have to
get out of here.
Shh!
Pushy.
That's Grant's truck.
Grant's never been anywhere
near this part of town.
Now, let's go. Please.
Pushy, look.
Come on.
Always be prepared, right?
Oh, my God! Pushy.
Look. He's coming.
Let's go. Run!
Hey! Get them!
Get them!
Come on, come on.
Go, go. Go!
If we make it through this,
I'm gonna kill you.
Leave us alone!
Look out!
Come on, go!
Jump! Jump!
Well, you happy now?
"Happy"? What do you mean?
You know, I have to
live around here!
You might wanna
think about that
once in a while!
This is getting
out of control, Dana.
Hey, come and get it.
It's firing.
Where were you
last night?
What?
Out with a couple of
mates having a few.
What are you, my wife?
Funny,
'cause I saw your truck
in the Umlazi township.
Umlazi?
Why would I go there?
We saw your license
plate, Grant.
We also saw what was
inside of your truck.
I reported it
to the police.
Used to have
a term for kooks
who got in way
over their heads on
a big day at Supers,
shark bait.
I think I'll take
this one in.
Yeah, you do that.
You didn't call the cops.
I bluffed.
And he didn't fold.
I'm not done with this.
She's 18.
She's my daughter.
I need to find her.
Sir, she's an adult.
We can put her photo in
our database and put out
a missing persons alert,
but I'm afraid there's
not much else we can do.
Next.
Look, how do l
access the database?
Next.
I can't believe I let
that creep con me
into actually liking him.
A guy so opposite to
everything I believe in!
What's so funny?
You're not that
different from Grant.
What? What's that
supposed to mean?
He's got a rich daddy.
You've got a rich daddy.
Face it, you're both just
spoiled kids playing at
being surf bums for a while.
And making trouble
for the rest of us.
Where the hell is
this coming from?
You think because
my father's rich that l
don't care about things?
That I don't feel pain?
You care about
what's important to you.
What?
You're dangerous.
And everyone else
gets dragged along
for the ride.
Hey, you volunteered
for this ride, remember?
Yeah, well, maybe
I'm getting off your bus.
I'm sick and tired
of living someone
else's dream.
This is your dream, too!
Right. And we both know Tara
is not gonna let that happen.
You're giving up?
Just leave me alone, Dana.
You know what?
Maybe Tara was
right about you!
No commitment and no guts!
Yeah? Thanks.
No problem.
Grant!
Hey, Dana.
Hey.
Well, I guess I need
a place to stay.
Just for one night.
I'm headed to
J-bay tomorrow.
You can
stay in our room.
Yeah, the more
the merrier.
Look, I think
it's your lucky day.
This cowpoke was gonna
bunk with Flash and Pete
over in Tim's bus.
Seems like a good opportunity
for you to, you know, do
some thinkin' up in my room.
Thanks, Cowboy.
Come on.
I'll help you
get set up.
Thanks, guys.
Have a good night.
Nice dreams.
Sorry, boys.
Hey,
if you change your mind,
I've got condoms.
You know,
Tim says swell's comin'.
Yeah, I guess.
Shit, right in time
for the Roxy tryouts.
I wonder if Tara's
really gonna be there.
Yeah, I heard she left
earlier today with Grant,
so I reckon
you ought to plan
on her being there.
She left with Grant?
After all that?
I don't think she knows.
I mean, does any of us
really know what happened?
Thanks for letting me
use your place.
You got it.
Dana! Dana!
I'm out of time and I'm afraid
I'll never get back home.
Dana. Dana? Dana,
where are you? Dana!
Pushy.
Everybody, get up!
Get up!
Pushy!
Everybody away
from the house now!
Attention.
Pushy!
The eThekwini Municipality,
by the order of the court,
is hereby
demolishing this
condemned building.
Any occupants
are hereby advised to
vacate immediately.
Pushy!
Pushy! Shit.
Damn it. Pushy!
Everybody
move to open sand for
a head count. Go!
Go. Come on, let's go.
Pushy!
Dana, I'm here.
I was looking for you.
Go! Run! Come on!
Pushy! Dana!
Come on! Come on!
Holy shit!
There goes our home.
Wait a minute. Tim.
Where's Tim?
Tim!
No way,
that thing runs!
Attention. Unofficial vehicles
are not allowed on the beach.
All aboard.
Who's coming aboard?
Bus leaves in five minutes!
Where to?
Jeffrey's Bay.
It's confirmed, swell of
the decade is on its way.
Let's go to J-bay.
Thanks for
coming after me.
So, you going?
You?
Only if you go.
You never give up,
do you?
Nope.
Then hell, yeah,
I'm going.
It's time you finished
your damn odyssey.
You and me,
we've got an appointment
with destiny in J-bay.
Hell, yeah, we do!
Look after yourselves,
okay?
Get on the bus, man!
No way.
You saved it all?
Hell, yeah.
Tim!
Hey, hey.
I'm driving. Come on.
Thank you.
Come on! Dana, Pushy, run!
Get on the bus!
Come on!
Move it!
Hello. I'm looking
for my daughter.
Her name's...
You're Dana's dad.
Yeah. Is she...
Is she here?
Nope. The whole family's
on the odyssey.
Chasing the swell, you know.
Well, except us folks.
Family? Odyssey?
Mmm. They're headed
down to Jeffrey's Bay.
But they got
three days on you.
And Lord knows where
they'll take off after that.
What's the fastest
way there?
Airplane.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm good.
You know,
we're technically
homeless now.
Well, we still
have the bus.
Yup, and a big, weird,
stinky family to fill it.
Yeah.
I'm just glad Pushy and l
are good again.
Yeah.
Man, I hope
she makes that team.
Tryouts are this Saturday,
that's two days away.
Yeah.
It's really great
how you supported her.
You're a really
special person, Dana.
Yeah? Do you wanna
write me a song about it?
I already did.
Oh, my God! You did?
Yeah.
How's it go?
It's complicated.
No kidding.
Come on,
let's hear it.
It is.
Yeah.
Whoo!
Go for it, Tim!
Thank you.
Okay, fasten your seatbelts,
hold on to your chickens,
we flyin'.
J-bay!
Yeah!
Wow.
We made it.
We did.
Whoa. I can see why
your mom wanted to surf it.
Why everyone
wants to surf it.
Yeah.
But maybe it's a boy's
club for a reason.
That wave is
a bone crusher.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I'm not afraid.
I'm gonna surf it
for my mom,
but I just can't help feeling
that I'm missing something.
Yeah?
What do you think it is
that I'm searching for?
Like, what do you
think this is about?
I think you should
turn around.
What? You mean go back?
No, I mean turn around.
Dad?
Hey, Dana.
Right. Well,
I'm gonna go.
Give you guys some space.
Tim. Tim.
Dana's dad is here.
Oh, wow.
The hell I am!
I am not going home.
Dana, I came halfway
around the world...
I didn't ask you to!
I'm your father!
Yeah? Since when?
Look, I know
you're going
through something,
but you have your
future to consider.
You have school
starting in the fall...
No.
That is your future,
that is your school.
It's not mine.
So... So what?
You're just going
to hang out here,
surfing and...
I mean, Jesus, Dana,
what are you doing here?
I mean, help me out here,
'cause I'm trying
to understand.
I mean, you wanna be
like your mother,
is that it?
Follow in her footsteps?
I mean, let it go,
Dana. She's dead!
Wow.
You really have a way
with words, Dad.
Dana, l...
Go home.
Just go home
and leave me
the hell alone!
Dana...
He thinks
that just by coming here,
it shows that he cares.
Well, it does.
Just saying.
What, you too?
You know,
what you're going through
is a really big deal.
Whether you
realize it or not.
You lost your mom.
We're sorry about that.
But are you ready to
lose your dad, too?
What? No.
That's not what...
Maybe it is.
Maybe that's the missing
piece of the puzzle.
Maybe that's why
you're really here,
to figure out the rest
of the puzzle,
before you lose that, too.
Wow.
Aren't you a smart boy.
Not so smart.
Hey, listen.
Unmistakable party sounds.
Hell, let's crash it.
I could use a distraction.
It looks like there's
a lot of Roxy people.
May be a chance to make
a good impression.
I don't know
about this.
Congratulations,
you made it.
Yep. I'll take
that 100 now.
Not just yet.
She still has to
surf Supertubes.
I will.
Change your mind
about trying out
for the team?
Nope. And neither did Push.
She'll be there.
Really?
That I can't
wait to see.
Really? What...
How you doing?
Crap. Come on.
Hey, Grant.
We need to talk.
Man, you don't
wanna do this.
People have told me things.
I don't wanna
believe them.
I wanna hear the truth
from my friend.
What things?
What are you
talking about?
Please, tell me
it isn't true, man.
Tell me it isn't true
about the tusks.
I'm outta here.
Answer the question!
Is it true?
Hey, hey, stop it!
Back off. This is
between the two of them.
Come on, guys,
that's enough.
That's enough!
Why?
I needed the money, bro.
I'm broke.
I was just the middleman.
I made a stupid mistake!
What, so you...
You bailing on me, too?
Give me one good
reason I shouldn't.
We know what it means and
we know what it takes,
so to us you're all winners.
I'm telling you,
they're gonna recognize me
from last night.
"There's that troublemaker."
Pushy, be serious.
They probably didn't
even notice us.
Nice seeing you again.
Thanks for ruining
the party last night.
She's okay.
I know her.
Seriously. She's cool.
Okay.
Put this on
over your wetsuit
and wait to be called.
Thank you.
So sorry.
Sorry.
Welcome, ladies,
to the Roxy team tryouts,
here at Phantom Reef
in the surf town
of Jeffrey's Bay.
It's one heat per girl,
two girls per heat.
You go head-to-head,
and you only have 10 minutes.
So, give it your best.
And if that isn't
enough pressure,
here to comment for us today,
straight from the world tour,
Roxy's own Sally Fitzgibbons,
and Laura Enever.
Hey, girls, I just wanna say
I know what it took for you
to be here today,
because four years ago,
this was us.
And make no mistake,
the competition's tough.
Especially since
we're only looking for
one more Roxy team rider.
By the end of today,
one of you is going
to be one of us.
Let the games begin!
Heat number one,
Savage and Nahoma.
Heat number two,
Jackson and Dottie.
Heat number three,
Hoffmeyer and Saville.
Okay, next heat.
Heat number four,
Cochran and Knotts.
Weak backside.
You'd kick her ass.
Okay, let's have
our final heat.
Kamalo and Bahn,
you're up.
Okay.
All you need is
one good ride.
One, and you get
to keep that vest.
Okay?
Let's do it.
Okay.
Kamalo and Bahn,
let's go!
Do me proud.
Right, Pushy!
Go, Pushy!
Come on, Pushy!
Come on!
Yeah, Pushy!
You know,
these girls worked so hard
and sacrificed so much.
It takes real guts
just to be out there.
That's gotta hurt!
Looks like purple
needs to shake it off
and get back out there.
Nice riding
for yellow, though.
Should be a good score.
Okay, watch the outside.
Come on.
What's that?
I remember this girl
from last year.
Yeah, so do I.
Only a handful of
black female surfers
have ever competed,
so we're witnessing
a little piece of history
right now.
How did you find this?
Well, it turns out when Grant
found out it was your thing
that that guy stole, he...
He knew?
Only after
you found his truck
and yelled at him.
But he took his sweet time
getting it back to you.
Probably because
ofyou and Tim.
You know,
male rivalry
and all that.
You've
got one minute.
One minute to go
in this heat.
This is it.
One minute to go
in this year's
Roxy team tryouts.
Come on, Pushy!
This is your time,
Pushy. Represent.
She better get
her ass going.
She's really going
to have to get moving to
get around this section.
Come on.
Come on, Pushy!
Okay, surfer's in position.
She's paddling hard.
Okay,
she's up and riding.
What's she gonna do?
Come on, Pushy.
Oh, my God!
Nice one.
She did it!
She pulled it off.
She did it! Yeah!
Wow.
That was the best surfing
we've seen all day.
Well, it took
a long time coming.
Yeah, it was a slow start
by purple, but that aerial
really made up for it.
We'll have to see what
the judges have to say.
Wouldn't wanna be
in their seats.
Everyone,
gather around.
We're gonna
have an announcement in
about two minutes' time.
You got it, okay?
That was
a lekker ride.
You need to work on
your consistency, though.
And you need to
read the waves.
So, we've got a big
decision to make here.
It's okay,
you've got this.
You killed it.
What do you think?
So, we're thinking
there's only...
Okay, ladies,
I know it's been
a tough competition.
You should all
feel like winners.
Unfortunately,
there's only one space
left on the Roxy team.
And our overall
winner today
is Pushy Kamalo.
Pushy!
Pushy! Pushy! Pushy!
So, welcome
to the team.
What took you so long?
Thank you.
And I want to thank
all of my friends
for feeding the fire.
Cheers.
And I want to thank you
for keeping me going.
Thank you.
Will you guys give me
a few minutes?
Take all the time you need.
I'm so proud of you.
So, do you
come here often?
Once every 20 years or so.
Can I show
you something?
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to upset you.
No, it's just
seeing these,
it brings back memories.
Your mother and l, we...
We took the same trip
that summer we met.
I know. That's why
I wanted to show you.
I also wanted to apologize.
I didn't mean
what I said last night.
It's weird,
but these past
couple of weeks
I've learned what it means
to be part of a family.
I understand.
After your mom died,
the truth is,
I couldn't handle it.
I just... I shut down.
I shut down when
you needed me the most.
You did all right, Dad.
You always found a way
to take care of me.
Too much sometimes.
I know.
And I was wrong
about that, too.
I tried to control you.
I was just so afraid
of losing you.
Just like I lost her.
And now I've lost you both.
You haven't lost me, Dad.
I think it's time.
You're home now, Mom.
One more thing left to do.
Hey, what's it like
out there?
It's firing.
Do you reckon
they'll let me in?
Um...
Yeah, I'm sure ifyou
show a little respect
you'll be fine.
It's actually pretty
heavy out there.
You sure you're in
the right place?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Okay, good luck.
Thanks.
Hey, locals only.
No lifeguards here,
sweetheart.
It's too hot for girls.
Seriously, get out of here.
Just leave before
you kill yourself.
All right, guys, guys.
Just chill, all right?
Just let her through.
She's cool.
Good luck.
I'm outta here.
Think you're tough?
Hey, kiddie beach
is down the way.
Go on, you don't belong
here. Get out of here.
Just go home.
Looks huge out there.
Yeah.
This is it.
Where is she?
Oh, shit.
I mean, she'll be fine.
I think.
Let's go up top.
Better view.
Hey, you okay?
Watch the waves.
You're tougher
than you look.
When you go, go.
Don't hesitate.
Go for it.
Come on,
you can do this.
Go for it,
you can do it.
Man, she's got it.
Whoo!
Yes!
Looked pretty
free-spirited to me.
Did you get
what you wanted?
Yeah.
I'm so proud of you.
Thanks, Dad.
Your mom would
have been, too.
Hit us with it, Cowboy.
Wait, tell us
what she was doing.
Oh!
Shut up!